Some workflows are much easier to demonstrate than to describe.
Teach turns one visible demonstration into a reusable Codex skill.
It is an open-source Codex plugin built for OpenAI Build Week with Codex and GPT-5.6.
Naming is optional.
Teach can infer it later, but recording never starts from the first request.
A separate ready action creates a short-lived consent record and starts this computer's native recorder.
I perform the task normally.
Teach captures the screen and pointer locally, with no raw keystroke log and no hidden background monitoring.
Now the configured Codex model reads bounded frames, structures the goal and steps, and checks which actions Codex can actually replay.
The live status makes longer analysis visibly active.
This is more than record and replay.
Teach labelises the process: goal, software, duration, risks, output contract, ordered steps, and capability-based replayability.
The model only drafts.
I can review and edit what it learned before anything is published.
Optimization is optional, and it is strict: an alternative must target the exact same output, not a cheaper or lower-quality substitute.
Once approved, Teach publishes a normal portable skill.
I can call it directly from a new Codex task.
Teach is Apache-2.0, stores inspectable files instead of a hidden database, and packages native paths for Linux, macOS, and Windows 11.
OpenAI Record and Replay validates the interaction.
Teach makes the idea open, cross-platform, richly labeled, and user-reviewable.
Show Codex once.
Keep the skill.